## Baishakhi Ray

Postdoctoral Researcher

Department of Computer Science Voice: (303) 748-2958

University of California Davis Email: bairay@ucdavis.edu

Davis, CA - 95616 http://rayb.info

#### **Research Interest**

My primary research interest is Software Engineering with a focus on empirical studies, program analysis, and software evolution. Using techniques from diverse domains including machine learning, natural language processing, and rigorous statistical modeling, I analyze large scale software repositories to understand on-going software engineering practices. This data-driven knowledge helps me to build novel program analysis techniques and development tools to improve software quality and programmer productivity.

#### **Education**

### Ph. D., Electrical & Computer Engineering, University of Texas, Austin.

August 2013 (GPA: 3.97)

Thesis: Analysis of Cross-System Porting and Porting Errors in Software Projects

Advisor: Miryung Kim

## MS, Computer Science, University of Colorado, Boulder.

August 2009 (GPA: 4.0)

Thesis: SecureWear: Securing Wearable Mobile Social Networks

Advisor: Richard Han

### B.Tech. & B.Sc., Computer Science & Physics, Calcutta University.

July 2004 (GPA: 3.84, Top 1% in University)

#### **Honors**

- Best Practical Paper Award, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy 2014
- Google Summer of Code 2012
- SIGSOFT FSE 2012 CAPS travel award
- Selected for admission to Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) for graduate study in Physics.
- Jawaharlal Nehru Summer Scholarship for Advanced Research, India 2001. (100 students are selected Nationwide).
- Ranked 6 out of 15,000 students in B.Sc. Physics(Hons.) examination.

# Research & Work Experience

### University of California Davis, CA, USA

Postdoctoral Research Fellow

Mentor: Prem Devanbu

October 2013 - present

## Microsoft Research, Redmond, USA

Research Intern May 2013–August 2013

Mentors: Christian Bird, Nachiappan Nagappan, Thomas Zimmermann

## Google Summer Code, Google Inc.

Research Intern May 2012 – August 2012

Mentors: Suzette Person, Neha Rungta, NASA

### The University of Texas at Austin, TX, USA

Graduate Student Researcher January 2011–May 2013

Adviser: Miryung Kim

## Avaya Research Lab, Westminster, CO, USA

Research Intern May 2008 – Aug 2008

Ericsson Pvt. Ltd. Boulder, CO, USA

Software Engineer February 2009–June 2010

Ixia, Sasken, and Texas Instruments, India

Software Engineer August 2004–July 2007

### **Selected Publications**

# **Full Length Research Papers**

- A Large Scale Study of Programming Languages and Code Quality in Github. B. Ray , D. Posnett , V. Filkov, P. T. Devanbu. In ACM SIGSOFT, 22<sup>nd</sup> International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE'14), acceptance rate: 22%
- Using Frankencerts for Automated Adversarial Testing of Certificate Validation in SSL/TLS Implementations.
   Brubaker, S. Jana, B. Ray, S. Khurshid, and V. Shmatikov
   In 35<sup>th</sup> IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, MAY, 2014 (S&P (Oakland) '14), acceptance rate: 13%, Best Practical Paper Award
- Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Inconsistencies in Ported Code. B. Ray, M. Kim, S. Person, N. Rungta. In 28<sup>th</sup> IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, November, 2013 (ASE'13), acceptance rate: 23%, Nominated for Distinguished Paper award, invited for ASE journal special issue.
- An Empirical Study of API Stability and Adoption in the Android Ecosystem. T. McDonnell, B. Ray,
   M. Kim. In 29<sup>th</sup> IEEE International Conference on Software Maintenance, April, 2013 (ICSM'13), acceptance rate: 22%
- 5. A Case Study of Cross-System Porting in Forked Projects. **B. Ray**, M. Kim. In ACM SIGSOFT, the 20<sup>th</sup> International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE'12), acceptance rate: 17%
- An Empirical Study of Supplementary Bug Fixes. J. Park, M. Kim, B. Ray, D. Bae. In The 9<sup>th</sup>
  IEEE Working Conference on Mining Software Repositories (MSR'12), acceptance rate: 28% Invited to
  the Special Issue of Journal of Empirical Software Engineering (EMSE).

- PTask: Operating System Abstractions To Manage GPUs as Compute Devices. CJ. Rossbach, J. Currey, M. Silberstein, B. Ray, E. Witchel. In Proceedings of the 23<sup>rd</sup> ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles (SOSP'11), acceptance rate: 17%.
- 8. A Protocol for Building Secure and Reliable Covert Channel. **B. Ray** and S. Mishra. In 6<sup>th</sup> Annual Conference on Privacy, Security and Trust, 2008. (PST'08).
- 9. WhozThat?: Evolving an Ecosystem for Context-Aware Mobile Social Networks. A. Beach, **B. Ray**, et al., In IEEE Network Magazine Special Issue on Composable context aware services, 2008.
- 10. SecureWear: A Framework for Securing Mobile Social Networks. **B. Ray**, R. Han. In Advances in Computer Science and Information Technology. Computer Science and Engineering, Lecture Notes of the Institute for Computer Sciences, Social Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering, 2012.

#### **Under Submission**

- 11. The Uniqueness of Changes: Characteristics and Applications. **B. Ray**, M. Nagappan, C. Bird, N. Nagappan, T. Zimmermann.
- 12. Assert Use in GitHub Projects. C. Casalnuovo, P. Devanbu, A. Oliveira, V. Filkov, B. Ray
- 13. *Gender and Tenure Diversity in GitHub Teams*. B. Vasilescu, D. Posnett, **B. Ray**, M. Brand, A. Serebrenik, P. Devanbu, V. Filkov
- 14. Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Porting Inconsistencies in Copy and Paste Code. **B. Ray**, M. Kim, S. Person, N. Rungta.

### **Short Papers**

- Repertoire: A Cross-System Porting Analysis Tool for Forked Software Projects. B. Ray, C. Wiley, M. Kim. In ACM SIGSOFT the 20<sup>th</sup> International Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering, Formal Research Tool Demonstration (FSE'12).
- 16. *Touch Me wE@r: Getting Physical with Social Networks*, A. Beach, **Baishakhi Ray**, L. Buechley. In 2009 Workshop on Sensor-based Models and Feedback Systems for Social Computing. associated with SocialCom 2009.

### **Software Releases**

- Frankencerts, https://github.com/sumanj/frankencert. Has received 51 github 'stars' as of October 2014.
- Repertoire, https://github.com/baishakhir/RepertoireTool. Forked 5 times in github, published in FSE'12 tool demo track

## **Teaching Experience**

### **Mentoring:**

- Saheel Godhane, Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Casey Casalnuovo, Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Vincent Hellendoorn, Visiting Graduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Connie Nguyen, Undergraduate Student, University of California, Davis.

- Abilio Oliveira, Undergraduate Student, University of California, Davis.
- Lisa Hua, Graduate Student, The University of Texas at Austin.
- Tyler McDonnell, Undergraduate Student, The University of Texas at Austin.

#### **Guest Lecturer**:

- Introduction to Programming and Problem Solving, Fall 2014, University of California, Davis
- Software Engineering, Fall 2013, University of California, Davis
- Software Engineering and Design Laboratory, Fall 2013, The University of Texas at Austin

Teaching Assistant: Mobile Computing, Fall 2010, The University of Texas at Austin

Grader: Operating Systems (Spring'08), Networking (Fall'08), University of Colorado, Boulder.

### **Academic Services**

## Program Committee.

- Mining Software Repositories, 2015 (MSR)
- Mining Software Repositories mining challenge, 2015 (MSR challenge)
- India Software Engineering Conference, 2015 (ISEC)
- Foundation of Software Engineering Artifact, 2014 (FSE Artifact)
- OOPSLA Artifact, 2013

#### Journal Reviewer.

- Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE)
- CSI Journal Computer Standards & Interfaces
- Information and Software Technology

### External Reviewer.

- Automated Software Engineering, 2014 (ASE)
- Mining Software Repository, 2012 (MSR)
- OOPSLA 2012

### Other.

 Vice President, Graduate Women in Engineering, ECE Department, The University of Texas at Austin

### **Invited Talks**

- Detecting and Characterizing Semantic Inconsistencies in Ported Code. NASA Ames, Mountain View, CA, November 2013.
- Analysis of Cross-System Porting and Porting Errors in Software Projects, Fujitsu Laboratories America, Sunnyvale, CA, January 2014

# **Media Coverage**

- Language Study [1]: SlashDot, The Register, Reddit, InfoWorld, Hacker News.
- Frankencerts [2]: Reddit, Golem, Heise.

### References

# Premkumar T. Devanbu

Professor

Department of Computer Science University of California, Davis Kemper Hall, 1 Shields Avenue Davis, CA 95616, USA

devanbu@cs.ucdavis.edu

### Sarfraz Khurshid

Associate Professor
Electrical and Computer Engineering Dept.
The University of Texas at Austin
1 University Station C5000
Austin, TX 78712, USA
khurshid@ece.utexas.edu

### **Thomas Zimmermann**

Researcher
Microsoft Research
1 Microsoft Way
Redmond, WA 98052, USA
tzimmer@microsoft.com

# **Miryung Kim**

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
University of California, Los Angeles
Boelter Hall, 420 Westwood Plaza
Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA
miryung@cs.ucla.edu

# Vitaly Shmatikov

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
The University of Texas at Austin
2317 Speedway
Austin, TX 78712, USA
shmat@cs.utexas.edu